# **Brandon Caples**

## SENIOR EMAIL MARKETING SPECIALIST

(423) 281-5150 brandon.caples@gmail.com brandoncaples.com







I'm a self-motivated senior email marketing specialist with 5 years of experience working collaboratively and individually to create beautiful and functional email campaigns using HTML, CSS, AMPscript, and other web technologies.

#### **SKILLS**

**EMAIL MARKETING** | Design and development, campaign strategy, segmentation, copywriting, Salesforce Marketing Cloud, ActiveCampaign, marketing automation, customer journeys, AMPscript, SQL, Luminate Online

EMAIL DEVELOPMENT | HTML, CSS, troubleshooting, AMPscript, VML, Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Git, SQL, project management, responsive design

**ANALYTICS & DATA** | Excel, Google Analytics, reporting, SQL/SOQL, Google Tag Manager, JavaScript, data analysis and reporting

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT | HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Timber/Twig, Ruby & Ruby on Rails, Liquid, WordPress, Shopify, CloudPages, PHP, MVC, Firebase, SVG animation

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Marketing Cloud Email Specialist Salesforce, 2024

Email Marketer HubSpot Academy, 2023

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts: Organizational Communication Lipscomb University — 2011

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Email & SMS Developer

Promoted from Digital Media & Web Developer in June 2024

Precept Ministries International — Chattanooga, Tennessee (Remote) December 2019 - PRESENT

#### **Email Marketing**

- Modernized email development processes, improving accessibility and render consistency across ESPs
- Design and query complex audience segments using SQL
- Created a modular component library for building HTML email templates
- Built 800+ responsive and performant emails, including email templates to be used by other contributors
- Launched and warmed a new email IP

## Team Leadership

- Train and mentor team members in email best practices, technical skills, content management, and business processes
- Provide guidance to team members for project delivery and prioritization
- Maintain technical documentation for marketing technology processes
- Recommend tactical approaches in alignment with technical feasibility

### **Analytics & Data**

- Report on email and web KPIs and supporting metrics
- Transitioned six web properties to Google Analytics 4
- Redefined how the organization tracks web engagement and wrote custom tracking scripts

## Frontend Web Development

- Developed new web components for fundraising campaigns
- Design and develop landing pages and website feature enhancements

# **Brandon Caples**

## SENIOR EMAIL MARKETING SPECIALIST

(423) 281-5150 brandon.caples@gmail.com brandoncaples.com







## Web Content Specialist

Mercy Multiplied America — Nashville, Tennessee

April 2018 - December 2019

I maintained website code and content, designed page layouts, optimized for search engines, and managed digital ads.

- Planned email campaigns, coded HTML emails, wrote email copy, and designed graphic assets
- Created and maintained event registrations and donation forms
- Revived a dead blog and developed its content plan and promotional strategy
- Designed and developed new content directories for mercymultiplied.com

# Digital Marketing Specialist

Columbia Coatings, LLC — Columbia, Tennessee

June 2017 - February 2018

I managed all email marketing, created website content, designed marketing graphics, and trained new associates for phone sales.

- Managed concept, design, and implementation of weekly email newsletter
- Retouched product photos and collected customer product photos
- Managed 4,000+ ecommerce products and general website performance
- Wrote, directed, and edited product tutorial videos

## Director of Client Communications, Deering Wealth Team

Southwestern Investment Group — Franklin, Tennessee

January 2016 - June 2017

I designed and launched a new website, wrote for the financial blog, coordinated client events, managed social media, and designed business collateral.

- Wrote and designed email communications, event collateral, website content, and blog posts
- Designed and launched deeringwealthteam.com
- Wrote, directed, and edited financial planning videos
- Planned, coordinated, and promoted client events and seminars

# Marketing Director

Batson Chiropractic Group — Nashville, Tennessee

August 2013 - January 2016

I wrote for blogs and the print newsletter, managed social media, and designed marketing collateral, among other duties.

- Oversaw ~60% business growth over 2½ years
- Increased monthly new patient average by 25.9% over previous two years •
- Grew Facebook following by 267%
- Designed and launched nashvillebraincore.com
- Automated the new patient intake process, avoiding human error and time costs during intake
- Designed marketing collateral, including website content, direct mail, newsletters, signage, email graphics, ads, etc.
- Designed and developed email customer journeys